tcd.ie 2014-06-25

# Privacy - Trinity College Dublin

* * *

## Privacy Statement

This is a statement of the practices of Trinity College Dublin (the "College") in connection with the capture of personal data on this website (that is all web pages within the domain www.tcd.ie) and the steps taken by the College to respect your privacy. The College is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites which may be accessed through the Trinity College website. It is College policy to identify clearly links to external websites and it is your responsibility to satisfy yourself as to the adequacy of the practices of linked sites. The College's policy regarding the use of College web resources may be inspected at [www.tcd.ie/Webdesign/policies/](http://www.tcd.ie/Webdesign/policies/index.php).

## General Statement

The College fully respects your right to privacy and actively seeks to preserve the privacy rights of those who share information with the College. The College will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your permission, except as may be required or permitted by law. Any personal information which you volunteer to the College will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, in accordance with the Data Protection Acts, 1988 and 2003. 

## Collection and Use of Personal Information

Any information which you provide in this way is not made available to any third parties, and is used by the College only in accordance with the purpose for which you provided the information and will only be retained for as long as required for the purpose. This is normally stated on the webpage where the information is requested and should be self-explanatory. However, if you have any specific queries about the purpose for which your information is to be used, you should contact our Information Compliance Officer before submitting the information. 

## Collection and Use of Technical Information

Information on internet traffic is collected routinely by the College and also at other points along the route in the internet (e.g. HEAnet). This technical information is used to ensure the smooth running of the computer network in the College and for statistical or administrative purposes. It is NOT used to gather identifiable personal information on individual website visitors, except in so far as this is permitted by law and may be necessary in order to prevent or detect problems or offences in relation to the operation of the website. 

## Cookie Policy

Please view our [Cookie Policy document](http://www.tcd.ie/about/policies/cookie-policy.php).

## Your Rights

Pursuant to the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003, you have certain rights to obtain a copy of the data held about you, for a fee. Any such requests should be made in writing (not email) to the Information Compliance Officer at the address set out below. For further details on your data privacy rights, please refer to [www.dataprotection.ie](http://www.dataprotection.ie/).

This statement should not be construed as a contractual undertaking. The College reserves the right to review and amend this statement at any time without notice and you should therefore re-visit this webpage from time to time. 

## Queries and Concerns

Any queries or concerns you may have about the processing of personal information on this website should be addressed to:

The Information Compliance Officer,  
Secretary's Office,  
West Theatre,  
Trinity College,  
Dublin 2 

Email: [information.compliance@tcd.ie](mailto:information.compliance@tcd.ie)  
Telephone: (01) 8962154  
Fax: (01) 6710037
